Get ready. Get set. Get nuts!
The Nut Job 2: Nutty by Nature is a animation, family,
adventure film directed by Cal Brunker.
When the evil mayor of Oakton decides to bulldoze Liberty Park and build a dangerous amusement park in its place, Surly Squirrel and
his ragtag group of animal friends need to band together to save their home, defeat the mayor, and take back the park.
Surly (voice), played by Will Arnett.
Precious (voice), played by Maya Rudolph.
Frankie (voice), played by Bobby Cannavale.
Mayor Muldoon (voice), played by Bobby Moynihan.
Heather (voice), played by Isabela Merced.
Gunther (voice), played by Peter Stormare.
The Nut Job 2: Nutty by Nature is a 2017 animated comedy film directed by Cal
Brunker and written by Brunker, Bob Barlen, and Scott Bindley.
The sequel to The Nut Job (2014) and based on the characters created by Peter Lepeniotis, it stars the voices of Will Arnett, Maya
Rudolph, Bobby Moynihan, Bobby Cannavale, Isabela Moner, Jeff Dunham, Gabriel Iglesias, Jackie Chan, and Katherine Heigl.
The film is an American–Canadian–South Korean co-production, produced by Gulfstream Pictures, Redrover International and ToonBox
Entertainment, and distributed by Open Road Films in the United States and The Weinstein Company in international.
The story follows Surly Squirrel and his animal
friends as they find out that Percival J.
Muldoon, the unscrupulous Mayor of Oakton City, plans to bulldoze Liberty
Park to make way for an amusement park named Libertyland.
They must join forces with Mr.
Feng and his mice to save Liberty Park and defeat the mayor.
Following the commercial success of its predecessor, Open Road announced a sequel in January 2014, with a planned
January 15, 2016 release date before being pushed back to a May 2017 release and finally August 2017 release.
Brunker replaced Lepeniotis as a director, while Brunker, Barlen,
and Bindley were brought on board to write the film.
Arnett, Rudolph, and the rest of the cast reprised their voice roles, with new
additions to the cast including Chan, Moynihan, Cannavale and Stormare.
The musical score was composed by Heitor Pereira,
replacing Paul Intson from the first film.
The Nut Job 2: Nutty by Nature was released theatrically on August 11, 2017.
Like its predecessor, the film was met with negative reviews and grossed
less with $68.7 million against a budget of $40 million.
A sequel is currently in development.
The film explores themes of squirrel, mayor, villain, anthropomorphism, animals.
The tone is lighthearted.